<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Publishing DTD v1.1 20151215//EN" "JATS-journalpublishing1.dtd"><article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.1" xml:lang="EN" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="hwp">lsa</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">lsa</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Life Science Alliance</journal-title><abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Life Sci. Alliance</abbrev-journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2575-1077</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Life Science Alliance LLC</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">LSA-2019-99999</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.26508/lsa.201999999</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="overline"><subject>Research Article</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Research Articles</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="hwp-journal-coll"><subject>0070</subject><subject>0090</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Polymorphisms of Adrenoceptors are not Associated with an Increased Risk of Adverse Event in Heart Failure: A MERIT-HF Substudy</article-title><alt-title alt-title-type="short">Der Pool der gemeinsamen Elemente</alt-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name><surname>Author</surname><given-names>Test A.</given-names><prefix>Dr.</prefix></name><degrees>MBBS, PhD</degrees><role>Professor</role><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">a</xref><xref ref-type="corresp" rid="cor1">&#x2a;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Auth&#xf3;r</surname><given-names>Test B.</given-names><suffix>Jr.</suffix></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">b</xref><xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Author</surname><given-names>Test C.</given-names><suffix>Gr. II</suffix></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3">c</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Author</surname><given-names>J.W.Th. Test Engineer</given-names></name></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>AUTHORS</surname><given-names>TESTER D.E.</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff4">d</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name><surname>Author</surname><given-names>Test D.</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>a</sup></xref><xref ref-type="corresp" rid="cor2">&#x2a;&#x2a;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Author</surname><given-names>Test E.</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff5">e</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><collab>ON BEHALF OF THE MERIT-HF STUDY GROUP</collab><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff6">f</xref></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff1"><label>a</label><institution>From the Division of Cardiovascular and Neuronal Remodelling, Leeds Institute of Genetics, Health and Therapeutics, University of Leeds, Leeds, UK.</institution></aff><aff id="aff2"><label>b</label><institution>Department of Cardiology, Pinderfields District Hospital, Wakefield, UK,</institution></aff><aff id="aff3"><label>c</label><institution>Biostatistics Unit, University of Leeds, Leeds, UK.</institution></aff><aff id="aff4"><label>d</label><institution>University Medical Centre Groningen, University of Groningen, The Netherlands,</institution></aff><aff id="aff5"><label>e</label><institution>Division of Cardiovascular and Diabetes Research, Leeds Institute of Genetics, Health and Therapeutics, University of Leeds, Leeds, UK</institution></aff><aff id="aff6"><label>f</label><institution>University of Exeter Business School, Streatham Court, Streatham Campus, University of Exeter, Exeter EX4 4ST, Devon, UK</institution></aff><author-notes><corresp id="cor1"><label>&#x2a;</label>Address for Correspondence: Test A. Author, PhD, Assistant Professor, University of Tennessee Health Science Center, Dept of Ophthalmology, Hamilton Eye Institute, 930 Madison Ave, Suite 722A, Memphis, TN 38163, Phone 901-448-1910, Fax 901-448-5028, <email xlink:href="dmahendren@tnqsoftware.co.in">dmahendren@tnqsoftware.co.in</email></corresp><corresp id="cor2"><label>&#x2a;&#x2a;</label>Address for Correspondence: Test D. Author, PhD, Assistant Professor, University of Tennessee Health Science Center, Dept of Ophthalmology, Hamilton Eye Institute, 930 Madison Ave, Suite 722A, Memphis, TN 38163, Phone 901-448-1910, Fax 901-448-5028, <email xlink:href="dmahendren@tnq.co.in">dmahendren@tnq.co.in</email></corresp><fn fn-type="other"><p>Received funding from Medical Research Council PhD Studentship (G78/8276).</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>This work was supported by NSF NYI grant CCR-9457806.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>This is dedicated to Rob.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>Presented by P. Walmsey</p></fn></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>0</day><month>0</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><month>8</month><year>2019</year></pub-date><elocation-id>e201701974</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>21</day><month>6</month><year>2019</year></date><date date-type="rev-recd"><day>25</day><month>6</month><year>2019</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>26</day><month>6</month><year>2019</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#xa9; 2019 Author et&#x20;al.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2019</copyright-year><ali:free_to_read xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/"/><license license-type="openaccess"><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="vor">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This article is available under a Creative Commons License (Attribution 4.0 International, as described at <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>).</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xlink:title="pdf" xlink:href="TNQ1580368500270.pdf"/><abstract abstract-type="executive-summary"><title>Highlights:</title><p><list list-type="number"><list-item><p>Freeze-thaw events noteworthy enhanced the accumulation of N<sub>2</sub>O emissions in boreal peatlands.</p></list-item><list-item><p>The enhanced N<sub>2</sub>O emissions during thawing were related to the availability of nitrate-N and denitrification.</p></list-item><list-item><p>There existed additive effects of FT events and nitrate-N addition that further increase N<sub>2</sub>O emissions in boreal peatlands.</p></list-item></list></p></abstract><abstract abstract-type="section"><title>Abstract</title><sec><title><bold>Background :</bold></title><p>Enhanced sympathetic activation has a central role in the development of heart failure (HF).</p></sec><sec><title><bold>Methods and Results :</bold></title><p>The distribution of &#x3b1;2C genotypes was similar between the event and nonevent groups. However, a reduced prevalence of the Del322-325 allele was found in individuals with ischemic congestive HF (P &#x3d; .022).</p></sec><sec><title><bold>Discussion :</bold></title><p>Environmental chemicals via the terrestrial food chain using crop-specific plant.</p></sec><sec><title><bold>Conclusions :</bold></title><p>The &#x3b1;2C Del322-325 polymorphism exclusively or in combination with the &#x3b2;1Arg389 allele is not associated with an increased risk of adverse events in HF.</p></sec></abstract><abstract abstract-type="graphical"><title>Graphical Abstract</title><p><fig id="absf1" position="float" fig-type="featured"><graphic xlink:href="LSA_99999_absf1"/></fig></p></abstract><abstract abstract-type="teaser"><p>This paper addresses exposure of children and adults to environmental chemicals via the terrestrial food chain using crop-specific plant uptake models.</p></abstract><abstract abstract-type="editor"><p>Editor&#x2019;s Abstract: This article will not appear on ScienceDirect, or MDConsult, Elsevier&#x2019;s premier electronic products</p></abstract><kwd-group><kwd>Compound heterozygous</kwd><kwd>Marfan syndrome</kwd><kwd>FBN1 mutation</kwd></kwd-group><kwd-group kwd-group-type="jel"><kwd>A1</kwd><kwd>F12</kwd><kwd>K155</kwd></kwd-group><kwd-group kwd-group-type="pacs"><kwd>61.34.&#x2b;ff</kwd><kwd>29.345&#x2b;r</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group id="nih-509"><funding-source country="US">NIH</funding-source><award-id>NIH GM61374</award-id></award-group></funding-group><funding-group><award-group id="nsf-510"><funding-source country="US">NSF</funding-source><award-id>NSF DBI-0317510</award-id></award-group><award-group id="arda-511" award-type="contract"><funding-source country="US">ARDA ACQUAINT</funding-source></award-group><award-group id="geneentech-512" award-type="gift"><funding-source country="US">Genentech Corp.</funding-source></award-group></funding-group><counts><page-count count="0"/></counts></article-meta></front><body><p>Enunciation 1: CP constraint and <italic>DP constraint should be used complementarily</italic>. DP constraint provides a powerful means to control the assignment of permissions. However, even among the permissions that have been assigned observing DP constraint, conflicting permissions may exist. In other words, DP constraint <bold>cannot solve a problem that is solved by CP constraint</bold>. CP constraint can resolve the conflict of interest between permissions. <italic>However, it is not possible to</italic> prevent a permission belonging to a <bold>cp</bold> <italic>from</italic> being assigned to multiple roles on which static separation of duty <sc>has been declared</sc>. In other words, CP constraint cannot solve a problem that is solved by DP constraint. Hence, if used together, they can limit the assignment of permissions more effectively.</p><sec sec-type="intro" id="s1"><label>1</label><title>Introduction</title><p>The introduction of new environmental technologies in production poses significant uncertainties for firms regarding the technologies&#x2019; future application possibilities [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B1">1</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2">2</xref>]. Life cycle Akinremi et al. (2001) analysis may lead to expectations of future developments of technologies. A definite statement about the future cannot, however, be made in an early stage of the life cycle. Accordingly, a foresight of the development of new technologies always includes an evaluation of a range of development possibilities.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn2"><sup>1</sup></xref></p><p>Scenario analysis is a very suitable foresight method that comprises the opportunity to include diverse influence factors for the description of multiple possible future development paths of a new technology [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B3">3</xref>]. The approach of this paper is to describe a classification of key influence factors for a scenario analysis for new technologies (technology scenario analysis) by Ananthakrishnan and Soman (1988 and 1989). Consequently, scenario <inline-formula><mml:math id="m5"><mml:mrow><mml:mi>&#x0394;</mml:mi><mml:mi>&#x03C1;</mml:mi><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:msub><mml:mi>&#x03C1;</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>d</mml:mi><mml:mi>x</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mo>-</mml:mo><mml:msub><mml:mi>&#x03C1;</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>d</mml:mi><mml:mn>1</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow><mml:mo>/</mml:mo><mml:msub><mml:mi>&#x03C1;</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>d</mml:mi><mml:mn>1</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:msub></mml:mrow></mml:math></inline-formula> analysis is enriched by a clearly defined approach to the study of the development Guhathakurta and Rajeevan (2007) of technologies. This renders a sound basis for a scenario analysis of technologies applicable to specific problems.<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn3"><sup>2</sup></xref><list list-type="simple"><list-item><label>1.</label><p>There is little measure consistency between the carbon calculators currently available&#x2013; i.e. the same journey would be measured at different levels of carbon emissions by different calculators</p></list-item><list-item><label>2.</label><p>Different calculators adopt different methodologies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B5"/><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B6"/>-<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B7">7</xref>]</p></list-item><list-item><label>3.</label><p>Most available calculators do not allow travel managers to evaluate supplier environmental performance as most calculators tend to treat all airlines as having the same performance for similar routes.</p></list-item></list></p></sec><sec id="s2"><label>2</label><title>Theory</title><p>Scenario analysis exemplifies a very suitable method of anticipating possible future developments of a new technology. Literature describes the procedure of scenario analysis comprehensively but while the basis for scenario analysis is the definition of influence factors in the development of new technologies, it remains mostly broad Bradley F. Murphy and Bertrand Timbal (2007) and lacks detailed description. Yet a clear determination of influence factors is crucial for such analysis. In this context, diffusion theory offers a sound description of factors that essentially influence the diffusion of a technology. The approach towards these factors has so far been mainly in an ex post (descriptive) manner. <chem-struct>2Na&#x2b;2H<sub>2</sub>O&#x3d;2NaOH&#x2b;H<sub>2</sub></chem-struct></p><sec id="s3"><label>2.1</label><title>Scenario analysis: General approach</title><p>The uncertainty that concerns technological development and the development of their business environment convinced many firms to employ scenario analysis [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B1">1</xref>]. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B8">8</xref>] defines scenarios as &#x201c;plausible representations of the future based on sets of internally consistent assumptions [&#x2026;] about relationships and processes of change [&#x2026;]&#x201c;. This presents scenario planning as the institutionalized process of conducting one or more scenario analyses as &#x201c;a disciplined method for imagining possible futures&#x201d; [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B9">9</xref>]. This approach distinguishes scenario analysis from forecasting as the latter is useful in the short term when predictability of developments Jagannathan and Bhalme (1973) is relatively high and uncertainty quite low owing to the low probability of disturbing events. In the long term, however, many developments are not clearly predictable and uncertainty can be significant [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B10">10</xref>]. Scenario analysis therefore focuses on the description of certain and uncertain trends, the underlying causal processes, and crucial decision points [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B11">11</xref>]. Hence, scenarios are more than just the &#x201c;technical&#x201d; output of simulation models, but they try to interpret such output by identifying patterns and clusters among the various outcomes. In addition, they often include elements that cannot be formally modelled very easily, such as new regulations, value shifts or innovations [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B3">3</xref>].<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn4"><sup>3</sup></xref></p><p>There are two approaches to scenario analysis: the normative and the exploratory approach. The normative approach aims at characterizing the way to achieve one of a number of possible future situations (scenarios). The exploratory approach takes past trends and the status quo as a starting-point, develops different future states, and analyzes Jagannathan and Parthasarathy (1973) the implications of these scenarios for strategic decision-making today [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B8">8</xref>]. This latter approach is applied in the analysis of future developments of biopolymers. Thus, it is not the intention to describe explicit steps to attaining a desirable future as it is in the normative approach. In practice, differing scenario methods for the exploratory approach exist [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B12">12</xref>], mainly varying in the number of steps. These steps can be classified in five categories, as in <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">Figure 1</xref>:</p><fig id="fig1" position="float" fig-type="featured"><label>Figure 1:</label><caption><title>Steps in exploratory scenario analysis [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B8">8</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B9">9</xref>].</title><p content-type="reference">Source: Akinremi, O.O. Journal of Climate, 14, 21-28. (Adapted from Medzhitov R, Janeway C Jr. Innate immunity. N Engl J Med 2000; 343:338&#x2013;344)</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="LSA_99999_fig1"/></fig><p>Literature about scenario analysis describes a rather broad definition of influence factors. They are usually derived from the thematic fields of economy, politics, society, technology and ecology. It lacks, however, especially in the case of new technologies, a clear description of influence factors that affect the future development of the technologies.</p><p><monospace>5&#x2032;-TACT.TTAC.ACAT.ATCA.CTTT.CTTT.CAAA.AATC-3&#x2032;</monospace></p></sec><sec id="s4"><label>2.2</label><title>Diffusion theory</title><p>Diffusion theory analyzes in which ways the use of an innovation spreads throughout a social system [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B13">13</xref>]. Therefore it examines &#x201c;the process of up-scaling&#x201d; innovations<xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn5"><sup>4</sup></xref> &#x201c;from small-scale to widespread use&#x201d; [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B15">15</xref>]. The aim of diffusion theory is to provide a framework of variables that influence the diffusion of innovations and their importance to the process of adoption. Hence, the emphasis is not on an exhaustive description of every particularity of a variable&#x2019;s effects [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B16">16</xref>].</p><p>Rogers&#x2019;s early work in [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B14">14</xref>] stimulated an era of research in the diffusion of technologies and is the basis for this analysis, enriched by the research of additional authors. According to him, the four main determinants of the diffusion process are those described in <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">Figure 2</xref>.</p><fig id="fig2" position="float" fig-type="featured"><label>Figure 2:</label><caption><p>Overview of the main determinants and the most influential attributes [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B14">14</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B17">17</xref><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B18"/>-<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B19">19</xref>].</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="LSA_99999_fig2"/></fig><p>All four determinants play an important role in the diffusion of an innovation. In order to identify technological influence factors ex ante, however, the focus is on the description of the perceived attributes of an innovation (see <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">Figure 2</xref>). The time factor as an important linkage to scenario analysis will be reflected mainly in the conduction of the scenario analysis.</p><p>In the matter of diffusion research the absolute newness of an idea and the objective attributes are less important in comparison with the perception of newness for an individual who gets hold of this idea and develops a subjective <xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="eq1">eq. (1)</xref> attitude towards this innovation. The rationale behind this is that the adoptive behaviour of potential users is widely determined <xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="eq2">eq. (2)</xref> by this perceived newness [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B14">14</xref>].<disp-formula id="eq1"><mml:math id="m6"><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">σ</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi></mml:msub><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:mi>ε</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:msup><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi mathvariant="bold">E</mml:mi><mml:mi>n</mml:mi></mml:msub><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:msub><mml:mi>E</mml:mi><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">N</mml:mi></mml:msub></mml:mrow><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mn>2</mml:mn></mml:msup></mml:mrow><mml:mo>/</mml:mo><mml:mn>2</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math><label>(1)</label></disp-formula><disp-formula id="eq2"><mml:math id="m7"><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">T</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi></mml:msub><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:msub><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">ε</mml:mi><mml:mn>0</mml:mn></mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi>E</mml:mi><mml:mi>n</mml:mi></mml:msub><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:msub><mml:mi>E</mml:mi><mml:mi mathvariant="bold">N</mml:mi></mml:msub></mml:mrow><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow><mml:mspace width="0.25em"/><mml:msub><mml:mi>E</mml:mi><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">T</mml:mi></mml:msub></mml:mrow></mml:math><label>(2)</label></disp-formula>where E<sub>T</sub> and E<sub>N</sub> are the normal electric field and tangential electric field strength induced by the electric pulse, respectively.</p><p>Within this list of attributes, relative advantage takes [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B17">17</xref><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B18"/>-<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B19">19</xref>] an outstanding position as it <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">Figure 2</xref> [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B14">14</xref>] has the largest impact on the diffusion of an innovation. Therefore the main focus of the analysis is on relative advantage. It is referred to as the &#x201c;degree to which an innovation is perceived as being better than the idea that it supersedes&#x201d; [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B21">21</xref>]and can be measured by the five factors presented in <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">Figure 2</xref> [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B14">14</xref>].</p><p>The higher is the satisfaction concerning these factors, the faster is the adoption and diffusion of an innovation. The type of relative advantage perceived as the most important for the adopter is likewise affected by the characteristics of the potential adopters and thus these characteristics indirectly contribute to the diffusion possibilities of an innovation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B14">14</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="s5"><label>2.3</label><title>Scenario analysis for new technologies</title><p>Generally, the above-mentioned steps for a scenario analysis remain valid for a technology scenario analysis. The first step in a technology scenario is a definition of the technology that needs to be more closely examined so the technology needs to be described in terms of the system of technologies that surrounds it [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B9">9</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B25">25</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B26">26</xref>].</p><p>What is special about this locality? Here we not only focussed on mapping the religious demography in our locality as such but also on the local history of every single group and the transformation processes they have gone through, caused by new demands from their members or users and for economic or political reasons.</p><p>What kinds of local, national, and global trends or discussions have formed this particular local group? In asking this question, we tried to uncover some of the local, national, and global discussions or agendas that seemed to have had an impact on local groups and their self-understanding.</p><p>For the definition of influence factors (step 2 in <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">Figure 1</xref>) two kinds, derived from diffusion theory, are included in technology scenario analysis, which constitutes the novelty of this approach: general and technology-specific factors. This classification results from the assumption that general influence factors have a universal impact on the analyzed technology as they do on other subjects, while technology-specific factors, derived from diffusion theory, influence the analyzed technology in a specific manner. Furthermore, general influence factors may also have an influence on technology-specific influence factors, such as the possibility that economic development may influence the perceived economic risk that a potential adopter faces in the adoption of a technology. The better the economic development, the more prepared the potential adopter might be to take the risk, and thus the lower the perceived risk. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B25">25</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B27">27</xref>]</p><p>In <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3">Figure 3</xref>, a composition of the above-described influence areas, including all main determinants of diffusion as described by [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B14">14</xref>], is proposed: in the figure there are two circles around the unit of analysis which describe the kinds of influence factors in order of the degree of generality of influence. In the outer circle general influence factors describe general evolutions as described in literature about scenario analysis. These also include society and thereby the social system in Rogers&#x2019;s diffusion theory. In the inner circle perceived attributes as technology-specific factors have a specific influence on the unit of scenario analysis. Additional to the attributes, the communication channel is also integrated in this circle as it is regarded as technology-specific (cf. <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">Figure 1</xref>) and as being of subjective nature (depicted in <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3">Figure 3</xref>) concerning the perception of the innovation. Time is included in the internal, autonomous development of the technology itself.</p><fig id="fig3" position="float" fig-type="featured"><label>Figure 3:</label><caption><p>Schematic illustration of the influence factors on a new technology including autonomous development. (Own illustration)</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="LSA_99999_fig3"/></fig></sec></sec><sec id="s6"><label>3</label><title>PLA blends and production technology</title><p>In general, the demand for plastics has increased during the last years and this development is likely to continue [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>]. The current level of world consumption is at 180 million tons and is expected to rise to 258 million tons in 2010. This corresponds to a per capita <xref ref-type="disp-formula" rid="eq4">equation (3) and (4)</xref> consumption of 24.5 kg today and 37 kg by 2010 [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B28">28</xref>].<disp-formula id="eq3"><mml:math id="m3"><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi>P</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mtext>pause</mml:mtext></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mo>&#x3d;</mml:mo><mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi>k</mml:mi><mml:mtext>b</mml:mtext></mml:msub></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi>k</mml:mi><mml:mtext>b</mml:mtext></mml:msub><mml:mo>&#x2b;</mml:mo><mml:mi>&#x3b3;</mml:mi><mml:msub><mml:mi>k</mml:mi><mml:mtext>e</mml:mtext></mml:msub></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac><mml:mo>&#x3d;</mml:mo><mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi>k</mml:mi><mml:mn>0</mml:mn></mml:msub><mml:mo>&#x2061;</mml:mo><mml:mi>exp</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mo>[</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mo>&#x2212;</mml:mo><mml:mi>F</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mo>/</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi>k</mml:mi><mml:mtext>B</mml:mtext></mml:msub><mml:mi>T</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mo>]</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi>k</mml:mi><mml:mn>0</mml:mn></mml:msub><mml:mo>&#x2061;</mml:mo><mml:mi>exp</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mo>[</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mo>&#x2212;</mml:mo><mml:mi>F</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mo>/</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi>k</mml:mi><mml:mtext>B</mml:mtext></mml:msub><mml:mi>T</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mo>]</mml:mo></mml:mrow><mml:mo>&#x2b;</mml:mo><mml:mi>&#x3b3;</mml:mi><mml:msub><mml:mi>k</mml:mi><mml:mtext>e</mml:mtext></mml:msub></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac><mml:mo>.</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:math><label>[3]</label></disp-formula><disp-formula id="eq4"><mml:math id="m9"><mml:mrow><mml:mi>x</mml:mi><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi>v</mml:mi><mml:mi>f</mml:mi></mml:msub></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>&#x03B3;</mml:mi><mml:msup><mml:mi>v</mml:mi><mml:mo>*</mml:mo></mml:msup></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:mn>2</mml:mn><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi>&#x03C1;</mml:mi><mml:mn>0</mml:mn></mml:msub><mml:mo>-</mml:mo><mml:msub><mml:mi>&#x03C1;</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>d</mml:mi><mml:mi>x</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:msub></mml:mrow><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi>&#x03C1;</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>d</mml:mi><mml:mi>x</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:msub></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac><mml:mo>,</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:math><label>(4)</label></disp-formula>where <italic>v</italic><sub><italic>f</italic></sub> is the average free volume per atom, <italic>&#x3c1;</italic><sub><italic>0</italic></sub> is the measured density (&#x3d;6.0619 g/cm<sup>3</sup>) of the sufficiently crystallized samples which was prepared by annealing at 773 K for 90 min, <italic>M</italic> is the averaged molar weight, <italic>N</italic> is Avogardo&#x2019;s number, <italic>&#x3b3;</italic> is the correction term, and <italic>v&#x2a;</italic> is the critical free volume value for atomic diffusion. The results of the calculated reduced free volume are displayed in <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4">Fig. 4(b)</xref>. Compared with the as-received samples, the reduced free volume of rods 2 and rod 3 significantly drops to around half and one-third, respectively, after annealing within the SLR. This means that the amount of reduced free volume strongly depends on the annealing temperature. Furthermore, it can be seen from <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4">Fig. 4(b)</xref> that warm deformation within the SLR also has a minor effect on the free volume reduction besides the annealing effect.</p><fig id="fig4" position="float" fig-type="featured"><label>Figure 4:</label><caption><p>Technology for the production of PLA blends in the surrounding technology system. (Own illustration)</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="LSA_99999_fig4"/></fig><p>Polymers are used for many applications like packaging and electronics as they have advantageous attributes compared with other materials, such as low weight, little energy requirement for production and processing as well as the option for an immediate reuse of production waste [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B29">29</xref>]. Indeed, the application possibilities of [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B30">30</xref><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B31"/>-<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B32">32</xref>] plastics, such as automotive parts that were formerly made from other materials, have increased during the last few years.<disp-formula id="e7"><mml:math id="m10"><mml:mrow><mml:msubsup><mml:mi>w</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mi>j</mml:mi><mml:mi>i</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mi>p</mml:mi><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mi>k</mml:mi></mml:msubsup><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:mn>1</mml:mn></mml:mrow><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:msubsup><mml:mi>w</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mi>j</mml:mi><mml:mi>i</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mi>p</mml:mi><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mi>k</mml:mi></mml:msubsup><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:mi>&#x0394;</mml:mi><mml:msubsup><mml:mi>w</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mi>j</mml:mi><mml:mi>i</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mi>p</mml:mi><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mi>k</mml:mi></mml:msubsup><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:mn>1</mml:mn></mml:mrow><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math><label>(5)</label></disp-formula><disp-formula id="e6"><mml:math id="m11"><mml:mrow><mml:msubsup><mml:mi>ν</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mi>j</mml:mi><mml:mi>i</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mi>p</mml:mi><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mi>k</mml:mi></mml:msubsup><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:mn>1</mml:mn></mml:mrow><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:msubsup><mml:mi>ν</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mi>j</mml:mi><mml:mi>i</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mi>p</mml:mi><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mi>k</mml:mi></mml:msubsup><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:mi>&#x0394;</mml:mi><mml:msubsup><mml:mi>ν</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mi>j</mml:mi><mml:mi>i</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mi>p</mml:mi><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mi>k</mml:mi></mml:msubsup><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:mn>1</mml:mn></mml:mrow><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math><label>(6)</label></disp-formula>where <inline-formula><mml:math id="m12"><mml:mrow><mml:mi>&#x0394;</mml:mi><mml:msubsup><mml:mi>w</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mi>j</mml:mi><mml:mi>l</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mi>p</mml:mi><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mi>k</mml:mi></mml:msubsup><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:mn>1</mml:mn></mml:mrow><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math></inline-formula> and <inline-formula><mml:math id="m13"><mml:mrow><mml:mi>&#x0394;</mml:mi><mml:msubsup><mml:mi>v</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mi>j</mml:mi><mml:mi>l</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mi>p</mml:mi><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mi>k</mml:mi></mml:msubsup><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:mn>1</mml:mn></mml:mrow><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math></inline-formula> are defined as in (7), respectively.</p><sec id="s7"><label>3.1</label><title>Biopolymers</title><p>Biopolymers mainly differ from traditional polymers by a change in the life cycle. The new focus on polymers based on renewable resources as well as on biodegradable polymers generates a new tendency of sustainability in the polymer industry [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B33">33</xref>]. The definition of biopolymers is, however, not uniform in literature [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B34">34</xref>-<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B35">35</xref>]. Biopolymers can be defined from the input point of view as polymers &#x201c;that have monomers, which are totally or mainly contained in the biomass, or which can be made from biomass using bio-technological processes&#x201d; [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B36">36</xref>]. Also, they can be defined as biodegradable polymers. The most common definition is the combination of renewable resources and biodegradability [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B7">7</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B30">30</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B37">37</xref>]. In this thesis the latter definition of biopolymers is mostly referred to unless otherwise described.</p><p>Degradable biopolymers in general are an interesting alternative to traditional plastics, especially for applications where recycling is impractical or uneconomical or when the environmental impact has to be minimized [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B7">7</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B38">38</xref>]. Bioplastics from renewable origin, either biodegradable or non-biodegradable, were in 2001 still a niche market as they required high efforts for material and application development [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B7">7</xref>]. In any case, the biopolymer sector grows continuously. The European consumption in 2003 was 40,000 <inline-formula><mml:math id="m14"><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi>D</mml:mi><mml:mi>k</mml:mi></mml:msub><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:munderover><mml:mo>Σ</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mi>i</mml:mi><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:mi>k</mml:mi><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:mn>1</mml:mn></mml:mrow><mml:mi>M</mml:mi></mml:munderover><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi>Q</mml:mi><mml:mi>i</mml:mi></mml:msub></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math></inline-formula> tons, which shows a doubling from 2001 [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B39">39</xref>]. Generally, the future of bioplastics is controversial and subject to many discussions and studies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B7">7</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B40">40</xref>]. Owing to this high development uncertainty, the subject of biopolymers and the corresponding production technology are an interesting topic for scenario analysis.</p></sec><sec id="s8"><label>3.2</label><title>PLA and PLA blends</title><p>Polylactic acid (PLA) is &#x201c;a degradable aliphatic polyester which can be completely produced from natural resources&#x201d; [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B41">41</xref>]. It was first produced in 1845 [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B42">42</xref>], and increased R&#x26;D efforts have been made from the 1980s on. Since the start of the production by NatureWorks in 2002, PLA has become the second type of biopolymer (on the basis of renewable raw materials) that has been commercialized and produced on a large scale [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B43">43</xref>].</p><sec id="s9"><label>3.2.1</label><title>Characteristics and applications of PLA today</title><p>The production of PLA is effected mostly by fermentation of plant sugars (starch) into lactic acid, which is then polymerized to polylactic acid (such as PLA from NatureWorks) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B7">7</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B32">32</xref>].</p><p>PLA and its copolymers have excellent properties concerning their applications in ecological, biomedical and pharmaceutical applications. The reasons therefore are [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B42">42</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B45">45</xref>]:<list list-type="simple"><list-item><label>1)</label><p>Anxiety may be an irrelevant comorbidity of bipolarity: it may be so common because bipolar disorder itself is severe and &#x2018;pulls in&#x2019; other diagnoses in part by ascertainment bias (a further diagnosis is more likely to be detected), in part via shared risk factors or even as a secondary effect of the primary psychopathology. However, this seems unlikely because the comorbidity is present across samples of bipolar disorder, including those drawn from the community, where severity is often modest. Moreover, schizophrenia does not show the same level of comorbidity, despite its comparable and, on some indices, greater severity.</p><list list-type="bullet"><list-item><label>&#x2022;</label><p>30 out of 34 reported studies reviewed were performed in animals</p></list-item><list-item><label>&#x2022;</label><p>The optimal access route and method could not be established</p></list-item><list-item><label>&#x2022;</label><p>Enterotomy closure could not be achieved reliably in all cases</p><list list-type="unsimple"><list-item><label>-</label><p>The production from renewable resources (e.g. from maize, wheat, sugar beet) and thus less dependency on oil.</p></list-item><list-item><label>-</label><p>The mechanical properties that are comparable with those of some traditional polymers (like polyethylene, polypropylene and polystyrene). Additional unique combinations of other excellent properties, such as strength, hardness, stiffness, elasticity, as well as good processability for injection moulding, extrusion equipment and film-blowing increases the application possibilities [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B49">49</xref>]. The high clarity, the high odour and flavour barrier, the high moisture barrier and the high resistance to grease and oil find many applications in packaging [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B42">42</xref>].</p></list-item><list-item><label>-</label><p>The degradability in the human body and in the natural environment.</p></list-item></list></list-item></list></list-item><list-item><label>2)</label><p>However, this seems unlikely because the comorbidity is present across samples of bipolar disorder, including those drawn from the community, where severity is often modest. Moreover, schizophrenia does not show the same level of comorbidity, despite its comparable and, on some indices, greater severity.</p></list-item></list></p><p>The physical attributes, hydrolysis and biodegradation behaviour of PLA depend on the alternation of their molecular characteristics and their ordered structures. The latter can be varied by different methods, for instance, polymer blending [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B42">42</xref>]. The word &#x201c;blending&#x201d; refers to an activity where different polymers are mixed in order to combine the characteristics of them all [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B44">44</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B50">50</xref>]. Blends still show many research possibilities for optimizing the combination of components with the goal of customized materials with optimal and complex attributes [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B42">42</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B51">51</xref>].</p><p>Products made of PLA on the market today are prototypes and pioneers. An overview of the main applications of PLA is given in <xref ref-type="table" rid="T1">Table 1</xref>. The global market for PLA [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B34">34</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B42">42</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B52">52</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B53">53</xref>]. blends grows continuously. The global market for PLA was in 2001 far lower than 4,000 t.p.a. In 2003/2004, the PLA market for films and non-woven/fibre products was about 122,000 t.p.a. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B43">43</xref>].</p><table-wrap id="T1" position="float"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>Specific rates of the increases in the extracellular (q<sub>P,ext</sub>) and intracellular (q<sub>P,int</sub>) levels of five dominant metabolites during the 24 h culture at 29&#xb0;C in which the carbon source was a CO<sub>2</sub>/N<sub>2</sub> gas mixture.<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="t1fna">a</xref></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><td rowspan="2"/><td colspan="3" align="center">q<sub>P,ext</sub><xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="t1fnb">b</xref></td><td colspan="3" align="center">q<sub>P,int</sub></td></tr><tr><td align="center">1.5 atm</td><td align="center">3 atm</td><td align="center">10 atm</td><td align="center">1.5 atm</td><td align="center">3 atm</td><td align="center">10 atm</td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Succinate</td><td>0.05</td><td>0.04</td><td>0.05</td><td>0.16</td><td>0.08</td><td>0.16</td></tr><tr><td>Lactate</td><td>0.0</td><td>0.01</td><td>0.03</td><td>0.69</td><td>0.49</td><td>0.85</td></tr><tr><td>Aspartate</td><td>0.0</td><td>0.0</td><td>0.33</td><td>3.28</td><td>2.28</td><td>1.93</td></tr><tr><td>Pyroglutamate</td><td>0.0</td><td>0.0</td><td>0.93</td><td>22.5</td><td>20.1</td><td>8.90</td></tr><tr><td>Glutamate</td><td>0.41</td><td>0.42</td><td>1.50</td><td>68.7</td><td>64.4</td><td>55.0</td></tr><tr><td>Total glutamate<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="t1fnc">c</xref></td><td>0.41</td><td>0.42</td><td>2.56</td><td>94.4</td><td>87.3</td><td>65.1</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn id="t1fna"><label>a</label><p>q<sub>P,ext</sub> and q<sub>P,int</sub> were calculated from equations [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B8">8</xref>] and [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B9">9</xref>] using the data in Supporting Information Table S1. &#x3bc; was assumed to be 0.234 hr<sup>-1</sup>. The pressures given in this table (i.e., 1.5, 3.0, and 10 atm) are the total pressures, which were initially controlled with a CO<sub>2</sub>/N<sub>2</sub> gas mixture at a 2:8 ratio (i.e., <inline-formula><mml:math id="m15"><mml:mrow><mml:msubsup><mml:mi>P</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>C</mml:mi><mml:mi>O</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>2</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>0</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:msubsup></mml:mrow></mml:math></inline-formula> : <inline-formula><mml:math id="m16"><mml:mrow><mml:msubsup><mml:mi>P</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>N</mml:mi><mml:mn>2</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>0</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:msubsup></mml:mrow></mml:math></inline-formula> &#x3d; 2:8).</p></fn><fn id="t1fnb"><label>b</label><p>Quantities given are in units of mg metabolite g cell<sup>-1</sup> hr<sup>-1</sup>.</p></fn><fn id="t1fnc"><label>c</label><p>Assuming the formation of pyroglutamate from glutamate, glutamate and pyroglutamate were considered as a single species, designated as total glutamate in this study. The values of q<sub>P,ext</sub> and q<sub>P,int</sub> of total glutamate were calculated as follows:<disp-formula id="uneq2"><mml:math id="m17"><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>q</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mtext>P,ext</mml:mtext></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mo stretchy="true">(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mtext>total glumate</mml:mtext></mml:mrow><mml:mo stretchy="true">)</mml:mo></mml:mrow><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>q</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mtext>P,ext</mml:mtext></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mo stretchy="true">(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mtext>pyroglutamate</mml:mtext></mml:mrow><mml:mo stretchy="true">)</mml:mo></mml:mrow><mml:mo>×</mml:mo><mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:mn>147</mml:mn></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>129</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>q</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mtext>P,ext</mml:mtext></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mo stretchy="true">(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mtext>glutamate</mml:mtext></mml:mrow><mml:mo stretchy="true">)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math></disp-formula><disp-formula id="uneq3"><mml:math id="m18"><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>q</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mtext>P,int</mml:mtext></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mo stretchy="true">(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mtext>total glumate</mml:mtext></mml:mrow><mml:mo stretchy="true">)</mml:mo></mml:mrow><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>q</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mtext>P,int</mml:mtext></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mo stretchy="true">(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mtext>pyroglutamate</mml:mtext></mml:mrow><mml:mo stretchy="true">)</mml:mo></mml:mrow><mml:mo>×</mml:mo><mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:mn>147</mml:mn></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>129</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>q</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mtext>P,int</mml:mtext></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mo stretchy="true">(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mtext>glutamate</mml:mtext></mml:mrow><mml:mo stretchy="true">)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math></disp-formula></p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><p>Generally, application possibilities of PLA blends are strongly influenced by their production costs, which have been very high owing to their complex chemical composition but tend to converge to those of petro-based polymers, partly because of the high oil price [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B37">37</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B38">38</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B42">42</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B43">43</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B54">54</xref>]. Recent developments in producing PLA at lower costs have been successful (US$ 1-2 per kg) and will thus accelerate their use as commodity plastics [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B38">38</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B42">42</xref>]. Therefore successful commercialization of PLA blends faces a major challenge in efficient processing and resulting cost reductions [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4">4</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B37">37</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B40">40</xref>].</p></sec></sec><sec id="s10"><label>3.3</label><title>PLA blend technology</title><p>Blending in general has the goal of cost-efficiently developing new types of polymers that combine the positive characteristics of the components and eliminate the less positive ones [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B55">55</xref>]. As described above, the physical properties of PLA depend mainly on chemical and phase structures which can be adjusted through changes in polymerization and processing conditions. One possibility of achieving this is by blending. Blending is more rapid and cost-efficient than other methods (e.g. chemical modification). One possibility to improve the mechanical properties of PLA is the usage of plasticizers to enhance processability, flexibility and ductility [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B41">41</xref>]. For biodegradable applications, the second component also needs to be biodegradable, which makes the process in some cases less economically attractive [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B49">49</xref>].</p><p>There are different types of blending technology. As a scenario analysis for a particular kind is too detailed for an outline of future development possibilities, the technologies were subsumed by a technology group referred to as &#x201c;PLA blend technology&#x201d;.</p><p>Thus, as PLA is used as input for PLA blends and as the output goes to further processing of the blends, the technology as a unit of analysis for the scenario analysis can be defined as in <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4">Figure 4</xref>.</p><p>Currently, PLA blend technology is mainly used by small companies. As a consequence, blends are either developed and tailored for specific customers (e.g. spin-offs of research institutes) or developed for a general type of application in small firms. In both cases, PLA blends are still produced on a small scale. This is in strong contrast to the production of PLA which is mainly in the hands of NatureWorks, who deliver to most PLA-processing firms.</p></sec></sec><sec id="s11"><label>4</label><title>Method</title><p>The theory described above as a basis for the scenario analysis, which can be classified as single-case study [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B56">56</xref>], was adapted to the case of PLA blend production technology. An extensive literature review led to a list of main influence factors, which were verified by several interviews with experts from industry and research. The scope of the scenario analysis was limited to the development of technologies for the production of PLA blends in the European Union (EU). The reason for limiting it to the EU is a conjoint regulatory framework of the member states. This framework is nevertheless not all-dominant but allows national regulations some degree of freedom.</p><p>Accounting for the opportunity of different development possibilities, one to three values were attached to every influence factor, depending on the categorization in a probable or in an uncertain future (cf. therefore also <xref ref-type="sec" rid="s13">section 5.1</xref>). As the development possibilities of an influence factor cannot be exhaustively enumerated, they were chosen in a manner that covers a wide range of developments. These values were then connected to consistent combinations by means of a decision tree, taking into consideration three types of consistency: trend consistency (compatibility of trends within the chosen time), stakeholder consistency (requires that the major stakeholders are not placed in positions they dislike and can change), and outcome consistency [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B3">3</xref>]. The outcome of 49 combinations was further clustered to seven aggregated scenarios. Owing to the lack of an appropriate computer program for a sufficient cluster analysis, the aggregation was conducted according to the importance of an influence factor for the combination. When an influence factor was regarded as less important than the other factors for a scenario, it was cancelled from the combination. All resulting combinations with an analogous mix of influence factor values were combined into a bundle that was considered as an aggregated scenario.</p><p>For a detailed description of scenarios, three aggregated scenarios were chosen according to the criterion whereby future opportunities were supposed to cover a wide range of development possibilities of PLA blend technology. Scenario 1 offers a closed view on the problem of political and economic dependency on oil and the possible resulting political actions. Scenario 2 focuses on social influence and on a differentiated development of ecological awareness. Scenario 3 covers the economic view of PLA blend technology with limited development possibilities. Therefore all three scenarios are archetypical with different theoretical foci on influence factors [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B9">9</xref>]: scenario 1 focuses on politics, scenario 2 on compatibility with needs and scenario 3 on relative advantage.</p></sec><sec id="s12"><label>5</label><title>Results</title><sec id="s13"><label>5.1</label><title>Choice of influence factors</title><p>The choice of influence factors for the scenario analysis depends in the first step on the time horizon which itself is influenced by the goal of the analysis. A time frame of roughly three decades is chosen.</p><p>In this framework, all influence factors contain three dimensions of characteristics as can be seen in <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5">Figure 5</xref>: they can be internal / external, general / technology-specific, and critical / uncritical. The latter characteristic refers to the range of possible or probable developments of influence factors which are referred to as &#x201c;values&#x201d;. Critical influence factors have multiple values, whereas uncritical factors have only one value [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B57">57</xref>]. As the multiple values of critical factors cannot completely be narrowed down, a scenario analysis can only contain a certain number of these values. Therefore a range of 1 (uncritical factor) to 3 (critical factor) values has been applied. The different values were chosen in a way to include a large range of development possibilities for the influence factor.</p><fig id="fig5" position="float" fig-type="featured"><label>Figure 5:</label><caption><title>Dimensions of influence factors [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B57">57</xref><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B58"/>-<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B59">59</xref>].</title><p content-type="reference">The outcome of the analysis is depicted in <xref ref-type="table" rid="T2">Table 2</xref>.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="LSA_99999_fig5"/></fig><table-wrap id="T2"><label>Table 2 :</label><caption><p>Descriptive statistic of the data obtained</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><td rowspan="2"/><td colspan="5" align="center">Moss</td><td colspan="5" align="center">Lichen</td></tr><tr><td align="center">Min.</td><td align="center">Max.</td><td align="center">Mean&#xb1;SD</td><td align="center">Skewness</td><td align="center">Kurtosis</td><td align="center">Min.</td><td align="center">Max.</td><td align="center">Mean&#xb1;SD</td><td align="center">Skewness</td><td align="center">Kurtosis</td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><sup>137</sup>Cs<sup>a</sup>(Bq kg<sup>-1</sup>)</td><td>201</td><td>4335</td><td>908&#xb1;848</td><td>2.7</td><td>8.6</td><td>132</td><td>1508</td><td>678&#xb1;387</td><td>0.7</td><td>0</td></tr><tr><td><sup>137</sup>Cs(Bq kg<sup>-1</sup>)</td><td>31</td><td>469</td><td>122&#xb1;100</td><td>2</td><td>4.2</td><td>45</td><td>287</td><td>125&#xb1;71</td><td>0.8</td><td>-0.2</td></tr><tr><td><sup>40</sup>K(Bq kg<sup>-1</sup>)</td><td>345</td><td>1435</td><td>814&#xb1;317</td><td>0.6</td><td>-0.7</td><td>347</td><td>2103</td><td>1073&#xb1;420</td><td>0.4</td><td>0.3</td></tr><tr><td>K(mg kg<sup>-1</sup>)</td><td>11</td><td>56</td><td>28&#xb1;11</td><td>0.6</td><td>0.3</td><td>13</td><td>54</td><td>30&#xb1;10</td><td>0.3</td><td>-0.1</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>The interrelation of the above-described influence factors can also be depicted analogously to <xref ref-type="sec" rid="s2">section 2</xref>, as in <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6">Figure 6</xref>.</p><fig id="fig6" position="float" fig-type="featured"><label>Figure 6:</label><caption><p>Influence factors on the development of the market and technology for PLA blends. (Own illustration)</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="LSA_99999_fig6"/></fig></sec><sec id="s14"><label>5.2</label><title>Scenarios for PLA blend technology</title><sec id="s15"><title>Scenario 1: Independence of oil</title><p>The continuously growing demand for oil and gas as feedstock for industrial production, transportation and heating causes a tight supply situation in the European Union. Owing to the increased worldwide demand, oil prices rise rapidly. Additionally, as the reserves in the North Sea decrease, the EU&#x2019;s import dependency on politically instable countries, where state-owned oil and gas producers control resources, grows dramatically. This development motivates politicians at EU and national member state level to increase subsidies for research and development that aims to replace fossil raw materials for various applications. The European industry is highly affected by the intended change in supply and implements adaptations for production as well as for products in order to use fewer fossil resources in the product life cycle. In particular, the plastics sector, whose principal feedstock is still oil, benefits widely from the financial support Supplemental Fig. 1 targeted at stronger efforts in R&#x26;D for alternatives to petro-based polymers. The political subsidies, the fast rise of the oil price, as well as the rising demand in plastics, encourage plastic producers to develop new types of polymers, e.g. by using new mixtures for blending, in order to reduce the fraction of petro-based input.<disp-quote><p>&#x201c;lying supine with the head flexed, hips flexed and knees flexed so as to adopt a foetal position. The head and legs were resting on rocks while the trunk was partially buried in loose soil. It was noted at the time that the mandible was detached from the body and was lying nearby. After carefully displacing the surrounding sand and lifting the mummy, it was observed that the dorsum had been eroded away, and that a few vertebral bodies and ribs were lying in the soil. These were recovered. The conditions in the cave at the time were cool and dry and the mummy was lying in a relatively inaccessible yet well ventilated area of the cave&#x201d;</p><p>Source: (Wium, 1992)</p></disp-quote></p><p>The increased interest in non-petro-based polymers also fosters R&#x26;D in PLA blend technology. The intense R&#x26;D results in an expansion of possible properties of PLA blends which are applicable for an extended range of products. The improved characteristics of PLA blends like strength, heat resistance, durability, and high clarity make PLA blends attractive for different products. Mechanical and thermal properties, which enable the processing of PLA blends on traditional machines, further contribute to the strong attention that they attract. These excellent characteristics and the high oil price give rise to substitutions of petro-based polymers by PLA blends in many products. Examples of these are short-term applications like pharmaceutical products and goods in the food service sectors as well as long-term products in electronics, construction and leather substitutions in the clothing industry.</p><p>As a result of the increasing market share of products made of PLA, the number of PLA-producing companies grows. The production of PLA blends on a large scale in all European countries causes a strong decrease of production costs owing to learning curves and economies of scale. The enhanced demand for agricultural commodities as feedstock rearranges the supply chain of the polymer sector. Opportunities of synergy effects (e.g. economies of scope) of both the agricultural and the plastics sector arise and strenuous efforts are made to reorganize industrial processes of transportation and processing. Cooperation between both sectors is intensified, mainly focusing on logistics. Furthermore, the success of the efficient synergy projects in the agricultural sector, thus on the input side of PLA producers, makes the PLA producers consider other synergies and reorganizations. Finally, they integrate PLA blend technology in their production.</p><p>PLA blend technology in the plants of large PLA producers is adapted to ensure a continuing downstream process of blend production after PLA production. Geographical transfers complement an adjustment of the size of the machines for large-scale production. The enlarged variety of different blends premises a parallel use of different blending technologies in one plant. On the other hand, technology for special applications adapted to customers&#x2019; needs remains in small firms that serve niche markets with small quantities.</p></sec><sec id="s16"><title>Scenario 2: Transient eco-markets</title><p>Environmental awareness undergoes a strong hype in the EU population and follows thus a worldwide trend in consumer sensitization towards health-related and environmental issues. Lifestyle changes, particularly in large cities in respect of human health and ecology, which causes a rethinking in topics of pollution, waste and security in order to reduce the negative impact on humans and nature. The trend that started in the beginning of the 21<sup>st</sup> century continues and buying patterns change to a fashionable attitude towards ecologically friendly products (so-called &#x201c;eco-products&#x201d;). The whole life cycle is taken into consideration, and labels of ecologically-friendly products represent a considerable marketing advantage for firms. Only some market segments can substantially benefit from eco-products, however, such as the food, packaging, and health care sectors. Others, like the automotive and the electronics sectors, do not experience an analogous demand for an environmentally-friendly product life cycle. Thus, buying behaviours fundamentally differ between lifestyle-products and products requiring a large investment.</p><p>The increased environmental awareness fades after some years, and the ecological compatibility of products becomes less important. Other attributes of products come to the fore, and firms pay less attention to the use of environmentally-friendly materials. The significance of environmental compatibility reaches a level where general concerns about pollution are theoretically accepted, but the buying behaviour is in all sectors primarily influenced by convenience considerations.<table-wrap id="unt01"><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><td>Excavated area</td><td align="center">MNI</td><td align="center">NISP</td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Dg1</td><td>12</td><td>96</td></tr><tr><td>Dg2</td><td>3</td><td>23</td></tr><tr><td>Dg3</td><td>3</td><td>24</td></tr><tr><td>Dg4</td><td>4</td><td>37</td></tr><tr><td>Dg5</td><td>2</td><td>23</td></tr><tr><td>Dg6</td><td>5</td><td>40</td></tr><tr><td>Dg7</td><td>-</td><td>1</td></tr><tr><td>Dg8</td><td>1</td><td>4</td></tr><tr><td>Total</td><td>30</td><td>248</td></tr><tr><td>Western cave (not excavated)</td><td>2</td><td>2</td></tr><tr><td>Total</td><td>32</td><td>250</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn><p>PLA blends remain a niche material that cannot keep up with other biopolymers</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></p><p>The greater environmental awareness lowers the price elasticity for eco-products during this time. As a consequence, firms start actively marketing the ecological friendliness Pant and Rupa Kumar (1997) of their products. The polymer sector reacts to this development by an expansion of the utilization of biopolymers. As both biodegradability and renewable feedstock of the materials are important issues for marketing, biopolymers with both attributes are particularly used. PLA blends meet both conditions and are thus subject to increased R&#x26;D that enhances properties and increases application possibilities for lifestyle products (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="figS1">Fig S1</xref>). PLA blend technology cannot, however, be sufficiently ameliorated and PLA blends show a lower application range in comparison with other biopolymers (such as starch-based plastics). Furthermore, some required characteristics can only be obtained by blending with petro-based and/or non-biodegradable polymers, which in turn diminishes firms&#x2019; marketing effects and sales <xref ref-type="fig" rid="figS2">S2B</xref>). Thus, PLA blends remain a niche material that cannot keep up with other biopolymers and PLA blend technology continues to serve a limited market.</p><fig id="figS1" position="float" fig-type="supplementary-material" specific-use="collapsible"><label>Figure S1.</label><caption><title>FACT correlates with active gene expression.</title><p><bold>(A)</bold> qPCR of <italic>Ssrp1</italic> levels among stem (mESCs), cancer (N2a and B16), and differentiated cell lines (MEFs and NIH3T3). Mean and SE of three biological replicates are shown. Data were normalised to <italic>Gapdh</italic> mRNA levels. <bold>(B)</bold> Heatmap assessing the mRNA levels (RPKM) of FACT (<italic>Ssrp1</italic> and <italic>Supt16</italic>) at different time points of differentiation of ES cells to cardiomyocytes (Wamstad et&#x20;al, 2012). <bold>(C)</bold> Distribution of SSRP1 relative to the TSS (&#xb1;2,000&#x20;bp) and the TES (&#xb1;2,000&#x20;bp) for four different gene classes ranked by the level of RNA abundance (high, medium, low, and very low). <bold>(D)</bold> Same as (C) but for SUPT16. <bold>(E)</bold> Scatterplot of the log<sub>2</sub> SSRP1 coverage versus log<sub>2</sub> mRNA expression. ESC, embryonic stem cells; MES, mesodermal cells; CP, cardiac precursors; and CM, cardiomyocytes.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="LSA-99999_FigS1"/></fig><fig id="figS2" position="float" fig-type="supplementary-material" specific-use="collapsible"><label>Figure S2.</label><caption><title>FACT depletion promotes increased proliferation rate in mESCs.</title><p><bold>(A)</bold> Western blots after transfection of mESCs with different combinations of <italic>Ssrp1</italic> shRNA vectors (shRNA 1 and 2 or shRNA 3 and 4). Anti-&#x3b1;-tubulin was used as a reference. <bold>(B)</bold> MTT assay following transfection with <italic>Ssrp1</italic> shRNA 3 and 4 vectors. Values are mean and SE of three independent transfection experiments are displayed. Significance was calculated via a <!--OPT:?A3B2 thyc=10?-->two-tailed<!--OPT:?A3B2 thyc?--> <italic>t test</italic> (&#x2a;<italic>P</italic>&#x20;&#x3c; 0.05).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="LSA-99999_FigS2"/></fig><p>The temporary increase of PLA blend production causes a small reduction of production costs because of learning curves and better production lines. Nevertheless, as environmental awareness levels off, the demand for PLA blends diminishes. The variety of PLA blends still remains an important source for specialized products that require characteristics where PLA blends have shown considerably better attributes than other plastics (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="figS3">Fig S3</xref>). PLA blend technology thus remains at the level of medium-sized firms. R&#x26;D in those firms is mostly concentrated on a specific group of applications as demand becomes more sophisticated and production requires more specialization in types of blends. The machines for PLA blend production itself increase their throughput, but no fundamental changes occur.</p><fig id="figS3" position="float" fig-type="supplementary-material" specific-use="collapsible"><label>Figure S3.</label><caption><title>FACT facilitates alternative splicing of RNA transcripts.</title><p><bold>(A)</bold> Volcano plot of <!--OPT:?A3B2 thyc=10?-->depleted/enriched <!--OPT:?A3B2 thyc?-->proteins at H3K4me3 following <italic>Ssrp1</italic> depletion. <bold>(B)</bold> Bar plots representing the number of <!--OPT:?A3B2 thyc=10?-->included/skipped <!--OPT:?A3B2 thyc?-->exons categorized by their gene expression status (red: &#x201c;down-regulated,&#x201d; cyan: &#x201c;unchanged,&#x201d; and blue: &#x201c;up-regulated&#x201d;). In total, we have identified 149 included and 207 skipped exon events in the <italic>Ssrp1</italic> KD group. <bold>(C)</bold> Graphical representation of an intronic retention event (<italic>Men1</italic>) in the KD group. Also, analysis of intron inclusion events or isoform switches after FACT depletion. Unspliced transcript percentage was measured according to band intensity. <bold>(D)</bold> Gene ontology analysis of transcripts (<!--OPT:?A3B2 thyc=10?-->FACT-bound)<!--OPT:?A3B2 thyc?--> that display alternative exon usage between the two conditions.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="LSA-99999_FigS3"/></fig></sec><sec id="s17"><title>Scenario 3: Domination of petro-based polymers</title><p>Although the oil price remains at a high level and even increases, renewable resources do not compete with oil as feedstock. Production costs for plastics with renewable feedstock stay too high, and petro-based polymers persist in covering the bulk of the polymer market. Despite continued R&#x26;D in PLA blends, their production costs remain uncompetitive, and the range of application possibilities stays very small.</p><p>Additionally, the inconsistent legal framework of the EU in terms of environmental issues, as for example landfills, hampers an advancement of R&#x26;D for biopolymers. The overall aim to tighten regulatory framework concerning biodegradability of products or renewability of feedstock remains inconsistent. National interests dominate discussions and the resulting uncertainty about future regulations lets firms postpone costly R&#x26;D in biopolymers. Industry faces the challenge to respond to all regulations while maintaining economic production. Therefore the polymers sector uses PLA blends only for applications where their advantages outweigh the additional costs, such as agriculture, packaging, or when cost savings can take place in other areas like the amount of labour needed.</p></sec><sec id="s18"><title>R&#x26;D and PLA</title><p>PLA blend producing firms specialize in particular types of PLA blends that cover characteristics suitable for a large number of applications. Firms remain specialized and concentrate research on a limited amount of PLA blends. They maintain either small and entrepreneurial structured firms or are spin-offs of research institutes. Large scale PLA blend production does not take place and the customization of PLA production technology to the specific user&#x2019;s requirement remains. This customization is, however, mostly a minor adaptation <xref ref-type="table" rid="T3">Table 3</xref> of the technology. PLA blend technology continues to serve niche markets and is thus specialized in the production of customized blends<disp-formula id="uneq1"><mml:math id="m19"><mml:mrow><mml:mi>W</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>l</mml:mi><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mtext>%</mml:mtext><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mi>w</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>i</mml:mi><mml:mi>g</mml:mi><mml:mi>h</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mspace width="0.25em"/><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>f</mml:mi><mml:mspace width="0.25em"/><mml:mi>w</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mspace width="0.25em"/><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>l</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>d</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>w</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>i</mml:mi><mml:mi>g</mml:mi><mml:mi>h</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mspace width="0.25em"/><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>f</mml:mi><mml:mspace width="0.25em"/><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>m</mml:mi><mml:mi>p</mml:mi><mml:mi>l</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac><mml:mo>×</mml:mo><mml:mn>100</mml:mn><mml:mo>+</mml:mo></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>M</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>l</mml:mi><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mtext>%</mml:mtext><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mi>w</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>i</mml:mi><mml:mi>g</mml:mi><mml:mi>h</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mspace width="0.25em"/><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>f</mml:mi><mml:mspace width="0.25em"/><mml:mi>w</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mspace width="0.25em"/><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>l</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>d</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>w</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>i</mml:mi><mml:mi>g</mml:mi><mml:mi>h</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mspace width="0.25em"/><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>f</mml:mi><mml:mspace width="0.25em"/><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>m</mml:mi><mml:mi>p</mml:mi><mml:mi>l</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac><mml:mo>×</mml:mo><mml:mn>200</mml:mn></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>W</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>l</mml:mi><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mtext>%</mml:mtext><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mi>w</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>i</mml:mi><mml:mi>g</mml:mi><mml:mi>h</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mspace width="0.25em"/><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>f</mml:mi><mml:mspace width="0.25em"/><mml:mi>w</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mspace width="0.25em"/><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>l</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>d</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>w</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>i</mml:mi><mml:mi>g</mml:mi><mml:mi>h</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mspace width="0.25em"/><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>f</mml:mi><mml:mspace width="0.25em"/><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>m</mml:mi><mml:mi>p</mml:mi><mml:mi>l</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac><mml:mo>-</mml:mo><mml:mn>300</mml:mn><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mi>W</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>l</mml:mi><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mtext>%</mml:mtext><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math></disp-formula></p><table-wrap id="T3"><label>Table 3:</label><caption><p>Potential Barriers to the Use of NOTES in Clinical Practice (NOSCAR White Paper).</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr><td>&#x2022;Access to the peritoneal cavity<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="t3fn1">1</xref><break/>&#x2022;Enterotomy closure<break/>&#x2022;Prevention of infection (Transluminal contamination)<break/>&#x2022;Development of endo-suturing devices<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="t3fn2">2</xref><break/>&#x2022;Development of anastomotic (non-suturing) devices<break/>&#x2022;Spatial orientation<break/>&#x2022;Development of a multitasking platform to accomplish procedures<break/>&#x2022;Control of intra-peritoneal haemorrhage<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="t3fn3">3</xref><break/>&#x2022;Management of iatrogenic intra-peritoneal complications<break/>&#x2022;Physiologic untoward events<break/>&#x2022;Compression syndromes<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="t3fn4">4</xref><break/>&#x2022;Training providers</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn><p>J. Szczepanski is the first author.</p></fn><fn id="t3fn1"><label>1</label><p>For reasons for the long-lasting discussions about a definition, cf. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B35">35</xref>].</p></fn><fn id="t3fn2"><label>2</label><p>NatureWorks was at that time still called Cargil Dow.</p></fn><fn id="t3fn3"><label>3</label><p>Copolymers are polymers whose molecular chains consist of different monomers (molecules) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B44">44</xref>].</p></fn><fn id="t3fn4"><label>4</label><p>Cf. therefore also [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B46">46</xref><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B47"/>-<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B48">48</xref>].</p></fn><p content-type="reference">Summary of the experimental conditions for the warm extruded LM1B BMGs</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec></sec></sec><sec id="s19"><label>6</label><title>Discussion</title><p>The approach to combining scenario analysis with diffusion theory offers the major advantage of a joint consideration of diffusion research and of the inclusion of uncertainty and different development possibilities Supplemental Table 1 in the anticipatory process. It offers the opportunity to specify the influence factors that have a strong impact on the diffusion of a technology for the purpose of scenario analysis.</p><p>The differentiation of external influence factors and the autonomous development of a technology enhance the approach and it is beneficial for the understanding of &#x201c;broad patterns of technological change that leads to specific strategic implications for technology management&#x201d; [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B27">27</xref>]. Furthermore, the application of the perception Treisman, 1993 of attributes as ex ante predictors of diffusion, which [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B60">60</xref>] have been used in the inner circle of <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3">Figure 3</xref>, is also suggested by Ostlund [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B18">18</xref>].</p><p>The described approach has a strong theoretical background but needs to be supported by practical implementation. It is also less clear whether the approach covers all issues that concern the interest of a technology (Aufderheide, 2003) manager or if a technology scenario approach needs to be enlarged in an additional direction in order to specify technology managers&#x2019; needs of the scenarios completely.</p></sec><sec id="s20"><label>7</label><title>Conclusion</title><p>The approach to combining exploratory scenario analysis and diffusion theory describes an advanced method of clearly defined influence factors for technology scenarios and thereby using diffusion theory in an ex ante manner. In this way technology scenario analysis as a technique is greatly improved. The enhanced method is very advantageous for policy-makers as well as for firms in elaborating a new technology&#x2019;s current position in terms of possible future developments.</p></sec><sec id="s21"><title>Supplementary Information</title><p>The Supplemental Data include Supplemental Experimental Procedures and One figures and One Table can be found with this article online at <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.cancercell.org/supplemental/S1535-6108(09)00073-7">http://www.cancercell.org/supplemental/S1535-6108(09)00073-7</ext-link>.</p></sec></body><back><ack><p>The authors thank C.P. Kim of Liquidmetal Technologies, Inc. for supplying the BMG samples used in this study. The XRD experiments at PLS were supported in part by MOST and POSTECH.</p><sec id="s22"><title>Conflict of Interest</title><p>The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</p></sec></ack><app-group><app id="app1"><label>Appendix</label><title>Comparison of flow power for different velocity field</title><p>Here we present a comparison of flow power for the two velocity fields (see section 3.1), <inline-formula><mml:math id="m20"><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi>u</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi></mml:msub><mml:mo>~</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mn>1</mml:mn><mml:mo>/</mml:mo><mml:mi>r</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math></inline-formula> and <inline-formula><mml:math id="m21"><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi>u</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi></mml:msub><mml:mo>~</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mn>1</mml:mn><mml:mo>/</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:msup><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mn>2</mml:mn></mml:msup></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math></inline-formula>.</p><p>The first velocity field is given by <disp-formula id="eqA1"><mml:math id="m22"><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi>u</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi></mml:msub><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:mfrac><mml:mi>u</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mi>α</mml:mi><mml:mo>-</mml:mo><mml:mn>1</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:mo>(</mml:mo><mml:mrow><mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:mi>α</mml:mi><mml:mi>R</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mi>r</mml:mi></mml:mfrac><mml:mo>-</mml:mo><mml:mn>1</mml:mn></mml:mrow><mml:mo>)</mml:mo></mml:mrow><mml:mi>cos</mml:mi><mml:mi>φ</mml:mi><mml:mo>,</mml:mo><mml:mspace width="0.25em"/><mml:msub><mml:mi>u</mml:mi><mml:mi>φ</mml:mi></mml:msub><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:mfrac><mml:mi>u</mml:mi><mml:mrow><mml:mi>α</mml:mi><mml:mo>-</mml:mo><mml:mn>1</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac><mml:mi>sin</mml:mi><mml:mi>φ</mml:mi><mml:mo>,</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:math><label>(A1)</label></disp-formula></p><p><inline-formula><mml:math id="m23"><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mi>W</mml:mi><mml:mtext>3</mml:mtext></mml:msub></mml:mrow></mml:math></inline-formula> is the power at discontinuity of tangential velocity on the boundary r &#x3d; R.where 147 and 129 are the molecular weights of glutamate and pyroglutamate, respectively.</p></app></app-group><fn-group><fn id="fn1"><label>1</label><p><bold>Author Footnote:</bold> Test.B. Auth&#xf3;r, Academic Unit of Cardiovascular Medicine, Leeds Institute of Genetics, Health and Therapeutics, Leeds, LS2 9JT United Nation</p></fn><fn id="fn2"><label>1</label><p>It was issued in September 2004 European Organisation for the safety of air navigation (BADA 3.6 Performance Summary Tables). The BADA database do not include many smaller aircraft type and therefore to miniise the use of "average" or "exemplar" aircraft in place of real aircraft, EEA data were used for the aircraft missing from the BADA dataset.</p></fn><fn id="fn3"><label>2</label><p>Although the authors recognise that some indirect flight paths are adopted by airlines to attract lower en-route air traffic charges.</p></fn><fn id="fn4"><label>3</label><p>For a critical appreciation of the method of scenario analysis, see [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B3">3</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B10">10</xref>].</p></fn><fn id="fn5"><label>4</label><p>The word innovation is often used synonymously with the word technology [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B14">14</xref>].</p></fn></fn-group><bio id="bio1"><p>Test A. Author is professor of biology and environmental studies at Dalhousie University. He obtained his Ph.D. in biology at Nottingham University in England. He moved to Canada in 1974. In 1991&#x2013;1996 he was chairperson of Dalhousie&#x27;s Biology Department, and currently serves in both the Faculty of Science and the Faculty of Management, working on the conservation and management of biodiversity, for which he has received several awards.</p></bio><glossary><title>List of abbreviations</title><def-list><def-item><term>GNAT</term><def><p>GCN5-related N-Acetyltransferase</p></def></def-item><def-item><term><sub>L</sub>-metsox</term><def><p><sub>L</sub>- methionine sulfoximine</p></def></def-item><def-item><term><sub>L</sub>-metsone</term><def><p><sub>L</sub>- methionine sulfo</p></def></def-item></def-list></glossary><ref-list><ref id="B1"><label>1.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Paivio</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Becker</surname> <given-names>LJ</given-names></string-name>, <etal/></person-group>, <article-title>Comparisons through the mind&#x2019;s eye</article-title>, <source>Cognition</source> <year>1975</year> <volume>37</volume>(<issue>2</issue>) <fpage>635</fpage>-<lpage>647</lpage></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B2"><label>2.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Koczkas</surname> <given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Holmberg</surname> <given-names>G</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Wedin</surname> <given-names>L</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>A pilot study of the effect of...</article-title> <source>Acta Psychiatrica Scandinavica</source> <year>1981</year> <volume>63</volume>(<issue>Suppl. 290</issue>) <fpage>328</fpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B3"><label>3.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="editor"><string-name><surname>Glaser</surname> <given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Bond</surname> <given-names>L</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>Testing: concepts and research</source>, <publisher-name>American Psychologist 36 (10&#x2013;12)</publisher-name> <year>1981</year>(<comment>special issue</comment>).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B4"><label>4.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Assink</surname> <given-names>EMH</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Verloop</surname> <given-names>N.</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Het aanleren van deel&#x2013;geheel relaties (Teaching part&#x2013;whole relations)</article-title> <source>Pedagogische Studien</source> <year>1977</year> <volume>54</volume> <fpage>130</fpage>-<lpage>142</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B5"><label>5.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Strunk</surname> <given-names>W</given-names> <suffix>Jr.</suffix></string-name>, <string-name><surname>White</surname> <given-names>EB</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>The elements of style</source>, <edition>3rd ed.</edition>, <publisher-name>Macmillan</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc> <year>1979</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B6"><label>6.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><collab>College bound seniors</collab></person-group>, <source>College Board Publications</source>, <publisher-loc>Princeton, NJ</publisher-loc> <year>1979</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B7"><label>7.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Luria</surname> <given-names>AR</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>The mind of a mnemonist (L. Solotarof, Trans.)</source>, <publisher-name>Avon books</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>, <year>1969</year>(<comment>Original work published 1965</comment>).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B8"><label>8.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Gurman</surname> <given-names>AS</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Kniskern</surname> <given-names>DP</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Family therapy outcome research: knowns and unknowns</article-title>, <person-group person-group-type="editor"><string-name><surname>Gurman</surname> <given-names>AS</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Kniskern</surname> <given-names>DP</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>Handbook of family therapy</source>, <publisher-name>Brunner/Mazel</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>, <year>1981</year>, <fpage>742</fpage>-<lpage>775</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B9"><label>9.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Sluzki</surname> <given-names>CE</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Beavin</surname> <given-names>J</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Symmetry and complementarity</article-title><person-group person-group-type="editor"><string-name><surname>Watzlawick</surname> <given-names>P</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Weakland</surname> <given-names>JH</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>The interactional view</source>, <publisher-name>Norton</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>, <year>1977</year>, <fpage>77</fpage>-<lpage>87</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B10"><label>10.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>van der Heijden</surname> <given-names>K</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>Scenarios: The art of strategic conversation</source>. <edition>2 ed</edition>. <year>2005</year>, <publisher-loc>Chichester, England</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Wiley</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B11"><label>11.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Chaddock</surname> <given-names>TE</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Gastric emptying of a nutritionally balanced diet</article-title><person-group person-group-type="editor"><string-name><surname>Daniel</surname> <given-names>EE</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>Proceedings of the Fourth International Symposium on Gastrointestinal Motility, ISGM4, 4&#x2013;8 September 1973, Seattle, WA</source>, <publisher-name>Mitchell Press, Vancouver</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>British Columbia, Canada</publisher-loc>, <year>1974</year>, <comment>pp. 83&#x2013;92</comment>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B12"><label>12.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="editor"><string-name><surname>Letheridge</surname> <given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Cannon</surname> <given-names>CR</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>Bilingual education</source>, <publisher-name>Praeger</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>, <year>1980</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B13"><label>13.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>van Slyke</surname> <given-names>C</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Lou</surname> <given-names>H</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Day</surname> <given-names>J</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>The impact of perceived innovation characteristics on intention to use groupware</article-title>, <source>Information Resources Management Journal</source>, <year>2002</year>, <volume>15</volume>(<issue>1</issue>): <fpage>5</fpage>-<lpage>12</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B14"><label>14.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Rogers</surname> <given-names>EM</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>Diffusion of innovations</source>. <edition>5th ed</edition>. <year>2003</year>, <publisher-name>Free Press</publisher-name>:<publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>. <comment>551</comment>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B15"><label>15.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Wilson</surname> <given-names>JG</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Basic teratology</article-title>, <person-group person-group-type="editor"><string-name><surname>Wilson</surname> <given-names>JG</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Fraser</surname> <given-names>FC</given-names></string-name> </person-group>, <source>Handbook of teratology</source>, <volume>1</volume>, <publisher-name>Plenum Press</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>, <fpage>1977</fpage>-<lpage>1978</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B16"><label>16.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"><person-group person-group-type="editor"><string-name><surname>Wilson</surname> <given-names>JG</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Fraser</surname> <given-names>FC</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>Handbook of teratology</source>, <volume>1&#x2013;4</volume>, <publisher-name>Plenum Press</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>, <fpage>1977</fpage>-<lpage>1978</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B17"><label>17.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Yu</surname> <given-names>F</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Wu</surname> <given-names>X-S</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>Phys. Rev. Lett.</source> <year>1992</year> <volume>68</volume> <fpage>2996</fpage>. <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="preprint:hep-th/9112009">preprint:hep-th/9112009</ext-link>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B18"><label>18.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Douglis</surname> <given-names>F</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Ball</surname> <given-names>Th</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Tracking and viewing changes on the web, in: Proc. 1996 USENIX Technical Conference</article-title>, <year>January 1996</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B19"><label>19.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"><collab>See the references in H.A. Buchdahl</collab>, <source>The Concepts of Classical Thermodynamics, first published by Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, 1966, also available electronically as: The Concepts of Classical Thermodynamics (last updated 1999). This reference discusses the basic concepts in a very thorough manner. Its literature list is a main entry point into the discipline</source></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B20"><label>20.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Thomas</surname> <given-names>W</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Znaniecki</surname> <given-names>F</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>The Polish peasant in Europe and America</source>, <year>1927</year>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Knopf</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B21"><label>21.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Rogers</surname> <given-names>E</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Schoemaker</surname> <given-names>F</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>Communication of innovations: A cross-cultural approach</source>, <year>1971</year>, <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Free Press</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B22"><label>22.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Tang</surname> <given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Liu</surname> <given-names>JM</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>Phys. Rev. Lett.</source>, <year>2003</year>, <volume>90</volume>, <fpage>194101</fpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B23"><label>23.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Black</surname> <given-names>CP</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Arlo</surname> <given-names>ST</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Rechit</surname> <given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Machlen</surname> <given-names>JP</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Sempson</surname> <given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Bee</surname> <given-names>AL</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Clark</surname> <given-names>SP</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <year>2001</year>, <source>APA format for psychology students</source>, <publisher-loc>Newark, NJ</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Prentice-Hall</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B24"><label>24.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Tornatzky</surname> <given-names>LG</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Klein</surname> <given-names>KJ</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Innovation characteristics and innovation adoption-implementation: A meta-analysis of findings</article-title>, <source>IEEE Transactions of engineering management</source>, <year>1982</year>. <volume>29</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>28</fpage>-<lpage>45</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B25"><label>25.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Geschka</surname> <given-names>H</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Technologieszenarien - Ein Analyse- und Planungsinstrument der Technologiemanagements</article-title>, <source>Technologiemanagement und Technologien f&#xfc;r das Management</source>, <person-group person-group-type="editor"><string-name><surname>Zahn</surname> <given-names>E</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <year>1994</year>, <publisher-name>Sch&#xe4;ffer-Poeschl</publisher-name>: <publisher-loc>Stuttgart</publisher-loc>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B26"><label>26.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Bood</surname> <given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Postma</surname> <given-names>T</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Strategic learning with scenarios</article-title>, <source>European Management Journal</source>, <year>1997</year>. <volume>15</volume>(<issue>6</issue>): <fpage>366</fpage>-<lpage>647</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B27"><label>27.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Adner</surname> <given-names>R</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Levinthal</surname> <given-names>DA</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>The emergence of emerging technologies</article-title>. <source>California Management Review</source>, <year>2002</year>. <volume>45</volume>(<issue>1</issue>): <fpage>50</fpage>-<lpage>66</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B28"><label>28.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Holdings</surname> <given-names>W</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>Bioplastics supply chains - Implications and opportunities for agriculture</source>. <year>2004</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B29"><label>29.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Brandrup</surname> <given-names>J</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source><italic>Polymers, polymer recycling, and sustainability</italic>, in <italic>Plastics and the environment</italic></source>, <person-group person-group-type="editor"><string-name><surname>Andrady</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <year>2003</year>, <publisher-name>Wiley</publisher-name>: <publisher-loc>Hoboken</publisher-loc>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B30"><label>30.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Kolybaba</surname> <given-names>MA</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Tabil</surname> <given-names>LG</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Panigrahi</surname> <given-names>SA</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>Recent developments in the biopolymer industry</source>. <year>2004</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B31"><label>31.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Ren</surname> <given-names>MA</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Biodegradable plastics: A solution or a challenge?</article-title> <source>Journal of Cleaner Production</source>, <year>2003</year>, <volume>11</volume>(<issue>1</issue>): <fpage>27</fpage>-<lpage>40</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B32"><label>32.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Gerngross</surname> <given-names>T</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Slater</surname> <given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>How green are green plastics</article-title>. <source>Scientific American</source>, <year>2000</year>. <volume>283</volume>(<issue>2</issue>): <fpage>36</fpage>-<lpage>41</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B33"><label>33.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Coombs</surname> <given-names>R</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Firm strategies and technological choices</article-title>, <source>Managing technology in society: The approach of constructive technology assessment</source>, <person-group person-group-type="editor"><string-name><surname>Rip</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Misa</surname> <given-names>T</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Schot</surname> <given-names>J</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <year>1995</year>, <publisher-name>Pinter Publishers</publisher-name>: <publisher-loc>London</publisher-loc>. <comment>p. 331-345</comment>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B34"><label>34.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Mohanty</surname> <given-names>AK</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Misra</surname> <given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Hinrichsen</surname> <given-names>G</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Biofibres, biodegredable polymers and biocomposites: An overview</article-title>. <source>Macromolecular Materials and Engineering</source>, <year>2000</year>. <volume>276</volume>(<issue>3-4</issue>): <fpage>1</fpage>-<lpage>24</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B35"><label>35.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>van der Zee</surname> <given-names>M</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Evaluation and certification of compostable polymeric materials and products</article-title>, <source>General aspects and special applications</source>, <person-group person-group-type="editor"><string-name><surname>Steinb&#xfc;chel</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <year>2003</year>, <publisher-name>Wiley</publisher-name>: <publisher-loc>Weinheim</publisher-loc>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B36"><label>36.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"><collab>UMSICHT</collab>, <source><italic>Annual Report 2004</italic>. 2004, Fraunhofer Institut f&#xfc;r Umwelt- Sicherheits- und Energietechnik UMSICHT</source></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B37"><label>37.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Lee</surname> <given-names>SY</given-names></string-name>, <etal/></person-group>, <article-title>Econimic aspects of biopolymer production</article-title>, <source>General aspects and special applications</source>, <person-group person-group-type="editor"><string-name><surname>Steinb&#xfc;chel</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <year>2003</year>, <publisher-name>Wiley</publisher-name>: <publisher-loc>Weilheim</publisher-loc>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B38"><label>38.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Bohlmann</surname> <given-names>GM</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>General characteristics, processability, industrial applications and market evolution of biodegradable polymers</article-title>, <source>Handbook of biodegradable polymers</source>, <person-group person-group-type="editor"><string-name><surname>Bastioli</surname> <given-names>C</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <year>2005</year>, <publisher-name>Rapra Technology</publisher-name>: <publisher-loc>Shrawbury</publisher-loc>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B39"><label>39.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"><collab>IBAW</collab>, <source><italic>Highlights in bioplastics</italic></source>. <year>2005</year></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B40"><label>40.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Miller</surname> <given-names>JA</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Nagarajan</surname> <given-names>V</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>The impact of biotechnology on the chemical industry in the 21st century</article-title>. <source>Trends in Biotechnology</source>, <year>2000</year>, <volume>18</volume>(<issue>5</issue>): <fpage>190</fpage>-<lpage>191</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B41"><label>41.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Lips</surname> <given-names>D</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>Polylactic acid / Natural fiber-composites - Materials and processing optimization</source>, <year>2001</year>, <publisher-name>Eidgen&#xf6;ssische Technische Hochschule</publisher-name>: <publisher-loc>Z&#xfc;rich</publisher-loc>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B42"><label>42.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Tsuji</surname> <given-names>H</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Polylactides</article-title>, <source>Humic substances, polyisoprenoids, polyesters, and polysaccharides</source>, <person-group person-group-type="editor"><string-name><surname>Steinb&#xfc;chel</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Marchessault</surname> <given-names>RH</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <year>2005</year>, <publisher-name>Wiley</publisher-name>: <publisher-loc>Weinheim</publisher-loc>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B43"><label>43.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Wolf</surname> <given-names>O</given-names></string-name>, <etal/></person-group>, <source>Techno-economic feasibility of large-scale production of bio-based polymers in Europe</source>, <year>2005</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B44"><label>44.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Michaeli</surname> <given-names>W</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>Einf&#xfc;hrung in die Kunststoffverarbeitung</source>. <year>1999</year>, <volume>4</volume>, <publisher-loc>M&#xfc;nchen, Wien</publisher-loc >: <publisher-name>Hanser</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B45"><label>45.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Galactic</surname></string-name></person-group>, <source>Biopolymers as viable alternatives to common plastics materials</source>. <year>2006</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B46"><label>46.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"><source>foodproductiondaily.com, <italic>Cost-competitive bio-degradable packaging tape developed</italic></source>. <year>2004</year></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B47"><label>47.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>FKuR</surname></string-name></person-group>, <source>Biologisch abbaubare PLA-Blends</source>. <year>2006</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B48"><label>48.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Patel</surname> <given-names>M</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Environemtal life cycle comparisons of biodegradable plastics</article-title>, <source>Handbook of biodegradable polymers</source>, <person-group person-group-type="editor"><string-name><surname>Bastioli</surname> <given-names>C</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <year>2005</year>, <publisher-name>Rapra Technology</publisher-name>: <publisher-loc>Shrawbury</publisher-loc>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B49"><label>49.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Kylmae</surname> <given-names>J</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Lactic acid based poly(ester-urethane) - Modification via copolymerization, chain linking and blending</article-title>, <source>Acta polytechnica scandinavia</source>. <year>2001</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B50"><label>50.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Menges</surname> <given-names>G</given-names></string-name>, <etal/></person-group>, <source>Werkstoffkunde Kunststoffe</source>. <year>2002</year>, <publisher-loc>M&#xfc;nchen, Wien</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Hanser</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B51"><label>51.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Radusch</surname> <given-names>H-J</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>Trends und Entwicklungen auf dem Gebiet der Polymerblends</source>. <year>2001</year>, <publisher-name>Martin-Luther Universit&#xe4;t</publisher-name>: <publisher-loc>Halle</publisher-loc>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B52"><label>52.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"><collab>NatureWorksLLC</collab>, <source>What can be made from PLA?</source> <year>2006</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B53"><label>53.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other"><collab>IDES</collab>, <source>PLA Overview</source>. <year>2006</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B54"><label>54.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Petersen</surname> <given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <etal/></person-group>, <article-title>Potential of biobased materials for food packaging</article-title>. <source>Trends in Food Science and Technology</source>, <year>1999</year>, <volume>10</volume>(<issue>2</issue>): <fpage>52</fpage>-<lpage>68</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B55"><label>55.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Heidemeyer</surname> <given-names>P</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Production of reinforced thermoplastics by blending with liquid crystalline polymers</article-title>, <source>Faculty of mechanical engineering</source>. <year>1990</year>, <publisher-name>RWTH</publisher-name>: <publisher-loc>Aachen</publisher-loc>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B56"><label>56.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Yin</surname> <given-names>R</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>Case study research</source>. <year>2003</year>, <publisher-loc>Thousand Oaks, London, New Delhi</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Sage</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B57"><label>57.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Missler-Behr</surname> <given-names>M</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>Methoden der Szenarioanalyse</source>. <year>1993</year>, <publisher-loc>Wiesbaden</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>DUV</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B58"><label>58.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Fink</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Schlake</surname> <given-names>O</given-names></string-name>, <string-name><surname>Siebe</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <source>Erfolg durch Szenariomanagement</source>. <year>2001</year>, <publisher-loc>Frankfurt</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Main: Campus</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B59"><label>59.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Wack</surname> <given-names>P</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Scenarios: Shooting the rapids</article-title>. <source>Harvard Business Review</source>, <year>1985</year>, <volume>63</volume>(<issue>6</issue>): <fpage>139</fpage>-<lpage>150</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref> <ref id="B60"><label>60.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><string-name><surname>Hargadon</surname> <given-names>AB</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <article-title>Diffusion of innovations</article-title>, <source>The technology management handbook</source>, <person-group person-group-type="editor"><string-name><surname>Dorf</surname> <given-names>RC</given-names></string-name></person-group>, <year>1999</year>, <publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name>: <publisher-loc>Heidelberg</publisher-loc>.</mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back><!--LRH: WADA-HIRAIKE et al--><!--RRH: ABERRANT LEIOMYOMA IN THE ABDOMINAL WALL--></article>